// 常见问题 数据
export const QUESTION_LIST_DATA = [{
  title: '企业信息',
  questionPartList: [{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团的使命是什么？',
    answer: '阿里巴巴集团的使命是“让天下没有难做的生意＂。我们的创始人是一群小企业的拥戴者，他们相信互联网能够创造公平的竞争环境，让小企业通过创新与科技扩展业务，并在参与国内或全球市场竞争时处于更有利的位置。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团于何时创立？',
    answer: '阿里巴巴集团由曾担任英语教师的马云为首的18人，于1999年在中国杭州市创立。公司起初主要经营网上批发贸易市场，让中国的小型出口商及创业者接触全球买家。'
  },{
    question: '公司为什么命名为“阿里巴巴”？',
    answer: '我们的主要创始人马云觉得世界各地的人士也认识有关“阿里巴巴＂的故事，而且大部份语言也存在类似的读音，因而将公司命名为阿里巴巴。电子商务是一门全球化的生意，所以我们也需要一个全球人士也熟悉的名字。阿里巴巴意谓“芝麻开门＂，喻意我们的平台为小企业开启财富之门。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团的总部设在哪里？',
    answer: '我们的主营业务的主要行政办公地点设在中国杭州市西溪区。'
  },{
    question: '公众可以参观阿里巴巴集团的企业园区吗？',
    answer: '阿里巴巴集团的企业园区位于杭州市西溪区，目前不对外开放。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团的办公室位于哪里？',
    answer: '我们在澳大利亚、中国、法国、德国、香港、印度、意大利、日本、韩国、荷兰、俄罗斯、新加坡、台湾、土耳其、阿联酋、英国和美国均设有办公室。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团有多少名员工？',
    answer: '截至2018年3月31日，我们共有66,421名员工。'
  },{
    question: '我们如何获得有关阿里巴巴集团的职位空缺资讯？',
    answer: '如欲获得有关我们的职位空缺资讯，请参见<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/global/careers">加入我们</a>。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团如何帮助社会？',
    answer: '阿里巴巴集团致力为社会创造价值，积极参与可持续发展的企业责任项目。欲了解更多信息，请参见<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/about/sustainability">可持续发展</a>。'
  }]
},{
  title: '业务信息',
  questionPartList: [{
    question: '阿里巴巴的核心业务是什么？',
    answer: '阿里巴巴集团为商家、品牌及其他企业提供基本的互联网基础设施以及营销平台，让其可借助互联网的力量与用户和客户互动。我们的业务包括核心电商、云计算、数字媒体和娱乐以及创新项目和其他业务。更多有关我们主要业务的资料，请参见<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/about/businesses">业务范畴</a>。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团的客户是谁？',
    answer: '我们的客户包括我们的交易市场上的买家和卖家，他们在该些平台上寻找对方、彼此选择并达成交易。买家可以免费使用我们的交易市场，而买家包括了随时随地在我们的零售市场上购物的消费者，以及通过我们的批发市场为自己的业务或为零售而采购产品的企业买家。卖家则可以使用我们的交易市场建立网上业务，并将产品和服务推广到数以亿计的消费者和其他企业。卖家包括了品牌商、零售商、批发商和制造商。我们也向不同类型的客户提供云计算服务，该些客户包括在我们的交易市场上经营业务的商家、系统集成商、移动客户端开发商及数字娱乐公司。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团所指的“阿里巴巴生态系统”是什么？',
    answer: '鉴于我们业务的规模，一个包括消费者、商家、品牌、其他企业、第三方服务供应商和战略合作伙伴在内的生态系统，已经围绕我们的平台和业务慢慢形成。这个生态系统的核心是我们的技术平台、市场规则以及我们扮演的角色——连通这些生态系统参与者，让其发现对方、互动和交易，并随时随地管理业务。我们付出的努力、时间和精神，多数都是用于对这个生态系统有利的举措及平衡各个参与者的利益上。我们认为维持这个生态系统的发展是我们的责任，因此我们称它为“我们的生态系统”'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团业务如何增长？',
    answer: '我们通过以下方式加强和扩大我们的生态系统，以实现长期增长：<br>-\t通过扩展业务的地域覆盖、增加产品和服务种类及改善消费者体验，提升活跃买家数及其消费水平<br>-\t将面向消费者的产品与服务由实体商品扩大至数字娱乐、医疗保健和本地服务<br>-\t重塑我们的平台成为品牌提升知名度和亲和力、管理并接触客户、扩大渠道以及创新产品的必然途径<br>-\t通过整合线上和线下资源、全渠道营销和分销、再造零售空间，并凭借大数据和世界级技术提升运营效率，为我们生态系统中的商家、品牌、零售商和其他企业创造价值<br>-\t将数据及云计算技术广泛应用于我们为客户及自身发展所进行的各类工作上<br>-\t继续在产品和技术上创新、变革商业模式和现有的产业价值链'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团的长远战略目标是什么？',
    answer: '我们的长远战略目标是服务全球20亿名消费者和支持1,000万家企业在我们的平台上盈利，为此，我们正致力于以下三方面的发展：全球化、农村发展以及大数据和云计算。'
  }]
},{
  title: '投资者信息',
  questionPartList: [{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团是在什么时候上市的？',
    answer: '阿里巴巴集团在2014年9月19日上市，上市时的定价为每股美国存托股（ADS）68美元。每股美国存托股相当于一股阿里巴巴集团普通股。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团在哪里上市？交易代码是什么？',
    answer: '阿里巴巴集团以美国存托股形式于纽约证券交易所上市，交易代码是BABA。如欲获取更多信息，请参考<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/stock">股价资讯</a>。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团的股息政策是怎样的？',
    answer: '我们目前没有任何派发股息的计划。我们打算保留全部或大部份的可用资金及未来的收益，用以经营和扩展我们的业务。未来的股息方案取决于<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/governance_6">董事会</a>的决定，董事们会考虑一系列因素，包括未来的经营情况、盈利能力、资金需求及盈余、一般财务状况、合约限制以及其他相关的因素，再作慎重的决定。'
  },{
    question: '我可以如何获取与投资者相关的阿里巴巴集团最新消息？',
    answer: '您可以于<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/home">投资者关系</a>页面订阅我们的RSS聚合新闻服务，以接收投资者相关的最新消息。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团跟软银集团和雅虎有什么关系？',
    answer: '软银集团和雅虎分别于2000年和2005年开始成为我们的股东。'
  }]
},{
  title: '财务报告',
  questionPartList: [{
    question: '我可以如何取得阿里巴巴集团的年度报告？',
    answer: '您可以<a href="http://otp.investis.com/clients/us/alibaba/SEC/sec-show.aspx?FilingId=12129538&amp;Cik=0001577552&amp;Type=PDF&amp;hasPdf=1" target="_blank">在此</a>浏览阿里巴巴集团的2017财年年报（包括经审计财务报表）。我们也会根据普通股股东和美国存托股股东的要求，免费提供年报的印刷版。如有需要，请联系阿里巴巴集团投资者关系部，地址为香港铜锣湾勿地臣街1号时代广场一座26楼。'
  },{
    question: '我可以如何知道阿里巴巴集团何时发布下一次财务业绩？',
    answer: '您可以浏览<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/newsevents">投资者新闻及活动</a>页面，查阅未来业绩公布日期，亦可以于<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/home">投资者关系</a>页面订阅我们的RSS聚合新闻服务，以接收最新消息。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团的财年何时结束？',
    answer: '我们的财年结束日是3月31日。'
  }]
},{
  title: '公司治理',
  questionPartList: [{
    question: '谁是阿里巴巴集团的董事？',
    answer: '您可以在<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/governance_6">这里</a>查阅阿里巴巴集团董事会的资料。'
  },{
    question: '什么是阿里巴巴合伙人制度？谁是阿里巴巴集团的合伙人？',
    answer: '有关阿里巴巴合伙人制度以及现任合伙人的资讯，请参见<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/governance_9">阿里巴巴合伙人制度</a>。'
  },{
    question: '阿里巴巴集团的管理团队包括了哪些成员？',
    answer: '您可以在<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/about/leadership">这里</a>查阅阿里巴巴集团领导团队的资料。'
  },{
    question: '谁是阿里巴巴集团的审计师？',
    answer: '阿里巴巴集团的独立外部审计师为普华永道。'
  },{
    question: '哪里可以找到更多有关阿里巴巴集团公司治理的资料？',
    answer: '您可以在<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/governance">这里</a>找到有关阿里巴巴集团公司治理的资料。'
  }]
},{
  title: '联络信息',
  questionPartList: [{
    question: '我可以联络谁查询投资者相关的问题？',
    answer: '如果您在此网站找不到需要的阿里巴巴集团资料，您可以<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/contact/contacts#slide_ir">联系我们</a>。'
  },{
    question: '我们如何联络阿里巴巴集团的客户服务团队？',
    answer: '阿里巴巴集团经营多项不同业务，每个业务团队有各自的客户沟通渠道。有关我们的主要业务及关联公司的联络方法，请参见<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/contact/contacts#slide_customer">客户联系</a>。'
  }]
}]

// 常见问题 数据
export const QUESTION_LIST_DATA_EN = [
  {
  title: 'Corporate Information',
  questionPartList: [{
    question: "What is Alibaba Group's mission?",
    answer: 'Our mission is "to make it easy to do business anywhere." Our founders started our company to champion small businesses, in the belief that the Internet would level the playing field by enabling small enterprises to leverage innovation and technology to grow and compete more effectively in the domestic and global economies.'
  },{
      question:"When was Alibaba Group founded?",
      answer:"Alibaba Group was founded in 1999 by 18 people led by Jack Ma, a former English teacher from Hangzhou, China. It began as an online wholesale marketplace for small Chinese exporters and entrepreneurs to reach global buyers."
  },{
      question:'Why is the company called "Alibaba"?',
      answer:'Jack Ma chose the name because it is well-known around the world and it can be easily pronounced in many languages. E-commerce is global so we needed a name that was globally recognized. Alibaba brings to mind "open sesame," representing that our platforms open a doorway to fortune for small businesses.'
  },{
      question:"Where is Alibaba Group headquartered?",
      answer:"The principal executive offices of our main operations are located in the Xixi District of Hangzhou, China"
  },{
      question:"Can the public tour the Alibaba Group corporate campus?",
      answer:"Currently, the Alibaba Group corporate campus, located in the Xixi District of Hangzhou, China, is not open to the public."
  },{
      question:"Where are Alibaba Group's offices located?",
      answer:"We maintain offices in Australia, China, France, Germany, Hong Kong, India, Italy, Japan, Korea, the Netherlands, Russia, Singapore, Taiwan, Turkey, the United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom and the United States."
  },{
      question:"How many people does Alibaba Group employ?",
      answer:"As of March 31, 2018, we had a total of 66,421 employees."
  },{
      question:"How do I learn about job openings at Alibaba Group?",
      answer:"To learn about our job openings, please visit the Careers page."
  },{
      question:"What is Alibaba Group doing to help the community?",
      answer:"Alibaba Group aspires to be a company that creates value for society. We are highly involved in sustainable corporate responsibility projects. For more information, please visit the <a href='https://www.alibabagroup.com/en/about/sustainability'>Sustainability</a> page."
  }]
},{
  title: 'Business Operations',
  questionPartList: [{
      question:"What is Alibaba Group's core business?",
      answer:"Alibaba Group provides the fundamental technology infrastructure and marketing reach to help merchants, brands and other businesses to leverage the power of the Internet to engage with their users and customers. Our businesses are comprised of core commerce, cloud computing, digital media and entertainment, innovation initiatives and others. For more information on our key offerings, please visit the <a href='https://www.alibabagroup.com/en/about/businesses'>Our Businesses</a> page."
  },{
      question:"Who are Alibaba Group's customers?",
      answer:"Our customers include both buyers and sellers on our marketplaces, and they discover, select and transact with each other on our platform. Buyers access our marketplaces free of charge. Buyers include consumers who come to our retail marketplaces to shop for anything anytime anywhere, as well as business buyers who use our wholesale marketplaces to source products for use in their own business or for resale. Sellers use our marketplaces to establish a presence on the Internet and market products and services to hundreds of millions of consumers and other businesses. Sellers include brands, retailers, wholesalers and manufacturers. We also provide cloud computing services to a wide range of customers including merchants doing business on our marketplaces, systems integrators, mobile app developers and digital entertainment companies."
  },{
      question:'What do you mean when you refer to the "Alibaba ecosystem"?',
      answer:'Given the scale we have been able to achieve, an ecosystem has developed around our platforms and businesses that consists of consumers, merchants, brands, other enterprises, third-party service providers and strategic alliance partners. At the nexus of this ecosystem are our technology platform, our marketplace rules and the role we play in connecting these participants to make it possible for them to discover, engage and transact with each other and manage their businesses anytime and anywhere. Much of our effort, time and energy is spent on initiatives that are for the greater good of the ecosystem and on balancing the interests of its participants. We feel a strong responsibility for the continued development of the ecosystem and we take ownership in this development. Accordingly, we refer to this as "our ecosystem."'
  },{
      question:"How does Alibaba Group grow its business?",
      answer:"We aim to strengthen and expand our ecosystem in order to achieve long-term growth by:<br/>\
      -	increasing active buyers and our wallet share through geographic expansion, new product and service categories, and improved consumer experience;<br/>\
      -	expanding product and service offerings to consumers beyond physical goods, including digital entertainment, healthcare and local services;<br/>\
      -	reinventing our platforms as go-to destinations for brands to lift awareness and affinity, manage and engage with customers, expand channels and innovate on products;<br/>\
      -	creating value for merchants, brands, retail operators and other businesses in our ecosystem through online and offline integration, omni-channel marketing and distribution, retail space reinvention and operational efficiency improvement driven by big data and world-class technology;<br/>\
      -	applying data and cloud computing technologies in everything we do for our customers and for ourselves; and<br/>\
      -	continuing to be an innovator in products and technology as well as a disrupter of business models and existing industry value chains.<br/>"
  },{
      question:"What is Alibaba Group’s long-term strategic goal?",
      answer:"Our long-term strategic goal is to serve two billion consumers around the world and support 10 million businesses to operate profitably on our platforms. Our key initiatives to achieve this strategic goal include: globalization, rural expansion and big data and cloud computing."
  }]
},{
  title: 'Investor Information',
  questionPartList: [{
      question:"When was Alibaba Group's initial public offering (IPO)?",
      answer:"Alibaba Group went public on September 19, 2014 at a price of $68 per American depositary share (ADS), each representing one ordinary share of Alibaba Group."
  },{
      question:"Where is Alibaba Group traded and what is the ticker symbol?",
      answer:"Alibaba Group's ADSs are traded on the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) under the ticker symbol BABA. You may refer to the <a href='https://www.alibabagroup.com/en/ir/stock'>Stock Information</a> page for further details"
  },{
      question:"What is the dividend policy of Alibaba Group?",
      answer:"We have no present plan to pay any dividends on our shares. We intend to retain most, if not all, of our available funds and any future earnings to operate and expand our business. Any future determination to pay dividends will be made at the discretion of our board of directors and may be based on a number of factors, including our future operations and earnings, capital requirements and surplus, general financial condition, contractual restrictions and other factors that the board of directors may deem relevant."
  },{
    question: 'How can I receive updates on investor news concerning Alibaba Group?',
    answer: 'Please visit the<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/home"> Investor Relations</a> section and subscribe to our RSS feeds'
  },{
    question: "What is Alibaba Group's relationship with SoftBank Corp. and Yahoo! Inc.?",
    answer: 'SoftBank Corp. has been our shareholder since 2000 and Yahoo! Inc. since 2005.'
  }]
},{
  title: 'Financial Reporting',
  questionPartList: [{
    question: 'How can I get a copy of the annual report of Alibaba Group?',
    answer: 'A digital copy of our FY2017 Annual Report, which contains the audited consolidated financial statements, is available <a href="http://otp.investis.com/clients/us/alibaba/SEC/sec-show.aspx?FilingId=12129538&amp;Cik=0001577552&amp;Type=PDF&amp;hasPdf=1" target="_blank">here</a>We will provide a hard copy free of charge to our shareholders and ADS holders upon request. Requests should be directed to:'
  },{
    question: 'How do I know when Alibaba Group releases its next financial results?',
    answer: 'You may visit the <a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/newsevents">Investor News and Events </a>page to find out our upcoming results announcement date. Alternatively, you may visit the<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/home">Investor Relations </a>section and subscribe to our RSS feeds to receive updates.'
  },{
    question: 'When is the fiscal year end of Alibaba Group?',
    answer: 'Our fiscal year ends on March 31.'
  }]
},{
  title: 'Corporate Governance',
  questionPartList: [{
    question: "Who sits on Alibaba Group's board of directors?",
    answer: 'Information on Alibaba Group’s board of directors can be found on the<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/governance_6">Board of Directors</a>page.。'
  },{
    question: 'What is the Alibaba Partnership? Who are the partners of the Alibaba Partnership?',
    answer: 'For information on the Alibaba Partnership and the current partners, please visit the<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/governance_9">Alibaba Partnership</a>page。'
  },{
    question: "Who is on Alibaba Group's management team?",
    answer: "Information on Alibaba Group's management team can be found on the <a href='https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/about/leadership'> Leadership</a>page."
  },{
    question: "Who is Alibaba Group's auditor?",
    answer: "Alibaba Group's independent external auditor is PricewaterhouseCoopers."
  },{
    question: 'Where can I find more corporate governance materials?',
    answer: "You can view Alibaba Group's corporate governance documents<a href='https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/ir/governance'>here</a>."
  }]
},{
  title: 'Contact Information',
  questionPartList: [{
    question: 'Who can I contact about investor-related issues?',
    answer: 'If you are unable to find the information you are looking for about Alibaba Group on this website, please<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/contact/contacts#slide_ir">contact us.</a>。'
  },{
    question: 'How do I contact your customer service team?',
    answer: 'Alibaba Group operates a range of businesses and each of them has its own customer communication channels. For the key contact information of our major businesses and affiliated entities, please visit the<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/cn/contact/contacts#slide_customer">Customer Service Contacts</a>page.'
  }]
}]


